A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - L-M, 2.5
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 359 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639B)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 34 minutes, 55 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an unidentified individual until 94 minutes, 2 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview Marshall interview with Marshall until end.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 3, circa 1980s; Sound, 282 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639C)
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 4, circa 1980s; Sound, 345 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639D)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 17 minutes, 17 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert Purcell until 73 minutes, 53 seconds. Purcell was president of IBEC and a financial advisor to the Rockefeller family. Tape then contains interview with Marshall until end.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 5, circa 1980s; Sound, 329 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639E)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 262 minutes, 4 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Bruce Gyory until end. Gyory was a political consultant.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 6, circa 1980s; Sound, 281 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639F)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 118 minutes, 30 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Thomas MacKell until 187 minutes, 3 seconds. MacKell was a New York state senator, 1955-1966, and district attorney of Queens County, 1967-1973. Tape then contains interview with Marshall until end.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 7, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9640)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc. Marshall interview ends at 65 minutes, 58 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview Peter Ogden until end. Ogden was an architect who collaborated with Nelson Rockefeller and also worked on IBEC housing projects.
    - Martin, June, circa1980s; Sound, 128 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9641)
      Interview. Martin was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Martindale, Steven, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9642)
      Interview. Martindale was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Massolo, Arthur, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9644)
      Interview. Massolo was a reporter for the New York Post and then gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Mathias, Charles, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9645)
      Interview. Mathias was a Republican politician from Maryland who served in the U.S. House of Representatives, 1961-1969, and the U.S. Senate, 1969-1987. Mathias interview ends at 63 minutes, 54 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Sandy Morhouse until end. Morhouse was the son of L. Judson Morhouse, who was Republican state chairman of New York.
    - McCrary, Tex, 1982 February 21; Sound, 189 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9646)
      Interview. McCrary was a radio and television personality, public relations specialist, and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller during the 1958 New York gubernatorial campaign. McCrary interview ends at 47 minutes, 59 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Rufus Miles until 93 minutes, 38 seconds. Miles worked at the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare while Nelson Rockefeller was the department's under-secretary. Tape then contains interview with McCrary until end, although the interview is unintelligible.
      Audio is highly distorted and unintelligible from 94 minutes until end.
    - McCray, Porter, circa1980s; Sound, 158 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9647)
      Interview. McCrary worked with Nelson Rockefeller when Rockefeller was the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs and at the Museum of Modern Art while Rockefeller was the museum's chairman.
    - McEneny, John J., circa1980s; Sound, 83 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9648)
      Interview. McEneny was head of the human resources department under Albany Mayor Erastus Corning. Tape begins with interview with unidentified individual until 10 minutes, 40 seconds
    - McEwen, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 62 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9649)
      Interview. McEwen was a Republican New York State senator, 1954-1964, and a member of the U.S. House of Representatives, 1965-1981.
    - McGovern, Joseph, circa1980s; Sound, 75 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9650)
      Interview. McGovern was a bond attorney who worked on the financing of the construction of the Empire State Plaza in Albany.
    - McKee, Jean, circa1980s; Sound, 91 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9651)
      Interview. McKee was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - McWhorter, Charles, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9652)
      Interview. McWhorter was a lawyer and aide to Richard Nixon.
    - Melich, Tanya, circa1980s; Sound, 189 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9653)
      Interview. Melich was an aide to Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Melich interview ends at 157 minutes, 35 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Miller, Alan, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9654)
      Interview. Miller was New York State Commissioner of Mental Hygiene, 1966-1975.
    - Miller, Dorothy - Part 1, 1982 November 23; Sound, 311 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9655A)
      Interview. Miller was a curator at the Museum of Modern Art and a consulatant and curator for numerous art projects for the Rockefeller family. Miller interview ends at 198 minutes, 3 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with investment banker Michel David-Weil until 208 minutes. Tape then contains no content until interview with Miller and an unidentified woman begins at 217 minutes, 28 seconds and lasts until the end of the tape.
      Speed becomes too fast at 206 minutes, and audio eventually becomes unintelligble from 208 minutes until 214 minutes, 20 seconds.
    - Miller, Dorotthy - Part 2, 1982 November 23?; Sound, 20 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9655B)
      Interview.
    - Miller, Irwin, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9656)
      Interview. Miller was an industrialist and chairman of the Rockefeller for President Commmittee during the 1968 presidential campaign. Interview with Miller begins at 2 minutes, 15 seconds and ends at 36 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Milton Gwirtzman until end. Gwirtzman was an advisor and speech writer for John, Bobby, and Edward Kennedy.
    - Mitchell, Donna, circa1980s; Sound, 141 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9657)
      Interview. Mitchell was a long-time associate of Nelson Rockefeller, beginning with his service in the Eisenhower administration on the committee to reorganize the federal government (PACGO/SCOGO) and then the newly created Department of Health, Education, and Welfare. Mitchell interview ends at 118 minutes, 48 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Edward Kresky until end. Kresky was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Mitrovich, George, circa1980s; Sound, 84 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9658)
      Interview. Mitrovich was press secretary for U.S. Senator Charles Goodell, who was apppointed by Governor Nelson Rockefeller to fill the seat after Senator Robert F. Kennedy's assassination in 1968. Interview was conducted by phone rather than in person. Mitrovich interview ends at 82 minutes, 7 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Edward Cain until end. Cain was chair of the Genesee County Republican Committee.
    - Moore, Beth, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9659)
      Interview. Moore was chairman of the board of the State University of New York and friend of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Moore, Jonathan, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9660)
      Interview. During the 1968 Republican presidential primaries, Moore was foreign policy advisor to Michigan Governor George Romney and then foreign policy advisor to Governor Nelson Rockefeller after Romney dropped out of the campaign.
    - Moreira Salles, Walther, circa1980s; Sound, 81 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9729)
      Interview. Moreira Salles was a Brazilian banker and philanthropist who was involved in IBEC. He was also Brazil's ambassador to the United States in the 1950s.
    - Morgenthau, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 25 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9661)
      Interview. Morgenthau was the 1962 Democratic nominee for Governor of New York.
    - Morhouse, Sandy, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9662)
      Interview. Morhouse was the son of L. Judson Morhouse, who was Republican state chairman of New York.
    - Morrison, Edward, circa1980s; Sound, 73 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9663)
      Interview. Morrison was Liberal Party of New York leader.
    - Mottahedeh, Mildred, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9664)
      Interview. Mottahedeh was a friend of Nelson Rockefeller and co-founded a company that produced porcelain reproductions for several United States presidents and museums. Mottahedeh interview ends at 30 minutes, 42 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert Stone until end. Stone served as Executive Deputy Secretary of State and then Deputy Commissioner of General Services under Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Moylan, Neal, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9665)
      Interview. Moylan was New York State Commerce Commissioner.
    - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, circa1980s; Sound, 133 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9666)
      Interview. Moynihan was a member of New York Governor Averell Harriman's staff. He also served in the administrations of Presidents John F. Kennedy, Lyndon Johnson, Richard Nixon, and Gerald Ford before representing New York in the United States Senate, 1977-2001. Moynihan interview ends at 57 minutes, 11 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Daniel Button until 104 minutes, 18 seconds. Button was assistant to the president of the State University of New York, 1952-1958; executive editor of the Albany Times Union newspaper, 1960-1966; and a Republican member of the United States House of Representatvies, 1967-1971. Tape then contintues with interview with Moynihan until 114 minutes, 6 seconds. Tape then contains two separate partial interviews with unidentified individuals until end.
    - Murray, J. Lawrence, circa1980s; Sound, 188 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9668)
      Interview. Murray worked for New York politician Frank Moore in various capacities during the 1950s and 1960s and served as acting chief administrative officer of the State University of New York, 1963-1964. Murray interview ends at 150 minutes, 49 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Gilder until end. Gilder was a speechwriter for Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Musicus, Milton, circa1980s; Sound, 85 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9669)
      Interview. Musicus served Governor Nelson Rockefeller as Assistant Secretary for Administration; later served on staff of Mayor John Lindsay. Musicus interview ends at 74 minutes, 20 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alexander Lankler until end. Lankler was a campaign aide to Governor Rockefeller.
  - N-P, 2.6
    - Nathan, Dick, circa1980s; Sound, 78 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9670)
      Interview. Nathan was an advisor to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and former director of the Rockefeller Institute of Government.
    - Neuberger, Roy, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9671)
      Interview. Neuberger was a financier, philanthropist, and art collector who knew Governor Nelson Rockefeller throught their mutual love of modern art. Neuberger interview ends at 76 minutes, 4 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Peter Cohen. Cohen was CEO of Shearson Lehman Brothers. The Cohen interview is not connected to Reich's Rockefeller book.
    - Newman, Bernard - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 41 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9672A)
      Interview. Newman was was counsel to the New York State Republican Party and was appointed to the New York State Supreme Court by Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Newman, Bernard - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 22 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9672B)
      Interview. Newman was a Republican leader who was appointed to the New York State Supreme Court by Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Nitze, Paul, circa1980s; Sound, 86 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9673)
      Interview. Nitze was director of the financial division of the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs under Nelson Rockefeller. Nitze interview ends at 53 minutes, 1 second. Tape then contains partial interview with Herbert Brownell until end. Brownell was United States Attorney General, 1953-1957.
    - O'Brien, Jr., Donal, circa1980s; Sound, 93 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9675)
      Interview. O'Brien was the Rockefeller family's lawyer for five decades.
    - O'Connor, Frank, and O'Donnell, Jim, circa1980s; Sound, 152 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9676)
      Interview. O'Connor was district attorney of Queens, 1955-1965, and the Democratic nominee for governor of New York in 1966. He was president of the New York City Council, 1966-1968, and a Justice of the New York State Supreme Court, 1969-1979. O'Donnell was an aide to O'Connor.
    - O'Neill, Abby, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9677)
      Interview. O'Neill was Nelson Rockefelelr's niece.
    - O'Shaughnessy, William, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9678)
      Interview. O'Shaughnessy was a broadcaster and writer. He was general manager of radio station WVOX in 1965 and bought the station three years later along with WTRN.
    - Ogden, Peter, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9679)
      Interview. Ogden was an architect for the Rockefeller's and IBEC Housing.
    - Oldenburg, Richard, 1982 May 5; Sound, 59 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9680)
      Interview. Oldenburg was director of the Museum of Modern Art, 1972-1995.
    - Ortiz, Arthur, 1982 November 9; Sound, 93 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9681)
      Interview. Ortiz was an American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) aide.
    - Ottinger, Richard, circa1980s; Sound, 45 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9682)
      Interview. Ottinger was a Democrat who served as U.S. Representative for the 24th and later 25th districts of New York from the 1960s to 1980s.
    - Parker, Gen. Theodore, circa1980s; Sound, 182 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9683)
      Interview. General Parker (U.S. Army) first served on the staff of Nelson Rockfeller during his tenure in the Eisenhower Administation as Special Assistant to the President for Foreign Affairs. Parker later served as New York State Commissioner of Transporation. Parker interview ends at 134 minutes, 50 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Richard Dunham until end. Dunham was deputy budget director and then director of the budget for Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Dunham was also deputy director of the White House Domestic Council when Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - Parkinson, Elizabeth - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9684)
      Interview. Parkinson was chairman of the Junior Advisory Committee at the Musuem of Modern Art at the invitation of Nelson Rockefeller. She subsequently helpd found the museum's International Council on which she served as president from 1957 to 1966. Parkinson interview ends at 35 minutes, 20 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an unidentified individual regarding investment banking that is unrelated to Reich's Nelson Rockefeller biography.
    - Parkinson, Elizabeth - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9700)
      Interview. Parkinson was chairman of the Junior Advisory Committee at the Musuem of Modern Art at the invitation of Nelson Rockefeller. She subsequently helpd found the museum's International Council on which she served as president from 1957 to 1966.
    - Peabody, Endicott, circa1980s; Sound, 31 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9686)
      Interview. Endicott was Governor of Massachusetts, 1963-1965. Interview begins at 3 minutes.
    - Perkins, Roswell B. - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9687)
      Interview. Perkins served on the staff of Nelson Rockefeller while he was Presidnet Eisenhower's Assistant Secretary for U.S. Health, Education, and Welfare Department; First Counsel to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller; Platform planning for 1960 and 1964 Presidential Campaigns.
    - Perkins, Roswell B. - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 333 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9688)
      Interview. Perkins served on the staff of Nelson Rockefeller while he was Presidnet Eisenhower's Assistant Secretary for U.S. Health, Education, and Welfare Department; First Counsel to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller; Platform planning for 1960 and 1964 Presidential Campaigns. Perkins interview ends at 312 minutes, 30 seconds. Tape then contains partial interivew with Sheldon Stark until end. Stark was a classmate of Nelson Rockefeller at the Lincoln School and Dartmouth.
    - Perrotta, Fiorvante (Fred), circa1980s; Sound, 281 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9689)
      Interview. Perrotta was assistant counsel to the Governor for Nelson Rockefeller; then New York City coordinator of Rockefeller's 1970 gubernatorial campaign. Perrotta interview ends at 127 minutes, 57 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Nelson Rockefeller's brother Laurance Rockefeller until 187 minutes, 16 seconds. Tapen then contains partial interview with Paul Nitze until 237 minutes, 12 seconds. Nitze was director of the financial division of the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs under Nelson Rockefeller. Tape then repeats part of Perrotta interview until 267 minutes, 37 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual regarding investment banking until end. This interview is not connected to Reich's Nelson Rockefeller biography.
    - Percy, Charles, circa1980s; Sound, 64 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9690)
      Interview. Percy worked on the Rockefeller Brothers Fund Special Studies Project. He was also a Republican Senator from Illinois, 1967-1985.
    - Phelan, circa1980s; Sound, 187 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9691)
      Interview. Phelan was aide to New York State Senate Majority Leader Earl Bridges. Phelan interview ends at 145 minutes, 12 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alton Marshall until end. Marshall was Governor Nelson Rockefeller's chief aide, 1965-1971, and later became president of Rockefeller Center.
    - Plaza, Galo, 1982 October 9; Sound, 93 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9692)
      Interview. Plaza was Ecuador's Ambassador to the United States, 1944-1946, President of Ecuador, 1948-1952, and Secretary General of the Organization of American States, 1968-1975.
    - Plumadore, Hayward, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9693)
      Interview. Plumadore was a New York Republican who served as Harrietstown Town Attorney and Supervisor; later was in the State Assembly representing Franklin County, and was county chair for the Republican party.
    - Price, John, circa1980s; Sound, 168 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9694)
      Interview. Price was a campaign aide for Governor Nelson Rockefeller's 1968 presidential campaign. John Price interview ends at 94 minutes, 1 second. Tape then contains partial interview with Robert Price until end. Price managed Nelson Rockefeller's 1964 Republican presidential primary campaign for Oregon.
    - Price, Peter, circa1980s; Sound, 159 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9695)
      Interview. Price was a laywer who worked on the Adirondack National Park proposal.
    - Price, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9696)
      Interview. Robert Price managed Nelson Rockefeller's 1964 Republican presidential primary campaign for Oregon. Price interview ends at 79 minutes, 13 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual regarding investment banking. This interview is not connected to Reich's biography on Nelson Rockfeller.
    - Prideaux, Tom, circa1980s; Sound, 180 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9697)
      Interview. Prideaux was a classmate of Nelson Rockefeller from the Lincoln School in Manhattan.
    - Purcell, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9698)
      Interview. Purcell was president of the International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC). Purcell interview ends at 71 minutes, 58 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Alton Marshall until end. Marshall was Secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and later became president of Rockefeller Center.
  - Q-R, 2.7
    - Reid, Ogden, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9702)
      Interview. Reid was appointed to the New York State Commission on Discrimination in 1961 by Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Reid also served six terms in the United States House of Representatives, 1963-1975. He switched from Republican to Democrat in 1972.
    - Robb, Lillemor Taylor (Lee), circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9704)
      Interview. Robb was the wife of newspaper publisher Gene Robb. She was also chairwoman of the New York State Commission on Judicial Conduct, 1975-1989.
    - Roberts, Al, circa1980s; Sound, 91 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9705)
      Interview. Roberts was staff director of the New York State Assembly Ways and Means Committee and member of the Albany Arts Council.
    - Roberts, Laurance, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9706)